Cariprazine, in a concentration-dependent (1⁻20 μM), significantly increased the intracellular accumulation of Rhodamine 123 in S1M1-80. 
Interestingly, 10 or 20 μM of cariprazine significantly decreased the expression levels of the ABCG2 protein in the colon and lung cancer cell lines, suggesting that cariprazine inhibits both the function and expression of ABCG2 transporters at nontoxic concentrations. 
Overall, our results suggest that cariprazine, via several distinct mechanisms, can resensitize resistant cancer cells to mitoxantrone.
Mutations in the RAS/RAF/MEK/ERK pathway leading to constitutive activation and uncontrolled cellular growth have been identified in various human malignancies, making this pathway a target for potential therapeutics. 
The activating IBM Watson for Oncology (WFO), which can use natural language processing to evaluate data in structured and unstructured formats, has begun to be used in China. 
It provides physicians with evidence-based treatment options and ranks them in three categories for treatment decision support. 
This study was designed to examine the concordance between the treatment recommendation proposed by WFO and actual clinical decisions by oncologists in our cancer center, which would reflect the differences of cancer treatment between China and the U.S.