Despite these failures, there still remains a push for more RCTs. 
In this commentary, we review the challenges that RCTs face in their ability to appropriately compare these two therapies.
Multidrug resistance (MDR) is a continuing clinical problem that limits the efficacy of chemotherapy in cancer. 
The over expression of the ATP-binding cassette (ABC) family G2 (ABCG2) transporter is one of the main mechanisms that mediates MDR in cancer. 
Molecular modeling data indicated that cariprazine, a dopamine D₂/D₃ receptor partial agonist, had a significant binding affinity for ABCG2 transporter with a Glide XP score of -6.515. Therefore, in this in vitro study, we determined the effect of cariprazine on MDR resulting from the overexpression of ABCG2 transporters. 
Alone, cariprazine, at concentrations up to 20 μM, did not significantly decrease cell viability. Cariprazine, at concentrations ranging from 1 to 10 μM, did not significantly alter the cytotoxicity of mitoxantrone (MX) in the parental non-small cell cancer cell line, H460 and colon cancer cell S1. 
However, cariprazine (1⁻20 μM) significantly enhanced the efficacy of ABCG2 substrate antineoplastic drug MX in the ABCG2-overexpressing MDR cell line, H460-MX20 and S1M1-80, by reducing the resistance fold from 28 to 1 and from 93 to 1.33, respectively.