Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) remains one of the most aggressive tumors with low life expectancy worldwide. 
The existence of cancer stem cells (CSCs) contributes to the failure of cancer treatment resulted from drug resistance. 
Altered microRNA expression has been observed in human tumors due to its role in tumor growth, progression and metastasis. 
Hence, the aim of our present study was to investigate the effects of miR-485 on the CSC-like traits in NSCLC A549-cisplatin resistant cells and concentrate on the underlying molecular mechanism. It was found that CSC-like phenotypes were much more enriched in A549/cisplatin (A549/CDDP) cells compared to A549-parental cells. 
In addition, we observed that miR-485 was greatly decreased in A549/CDDP cells and miR-485 overexpression was able to decrease the stemness of A549/DDP cells. 
Meanwhile, epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG), a green tea polyphenol which has been identified as an effective anticancer compound was able to increase miR-485 expression dose-dependently in A549/CDDP cells. 
Inhibitors of miR-485 remarkably increased CSC-like phenotypes, which could be reversed by indicated doses of EGCG. Moreover, CD44 was predicted as downstream target of miR-485 and the correlation between them was validated by performing dual-luciferase reporter assay and RNA immunoprecipitation (RIP) assay. 
Subsequently, in vivo experiments were employed to confirm that EGCG restrained CSC-like characteristics by increasing miR-485 and decreasing CD44 expression. Taken together, it was implied that stemness features and CSC population were suppressed by EGCG-modulated miR-485/CD44 axis in A549/CDDP cells. 
Actinomycosis is an uncommon infectious disease caused predominantly by Actinomyces israelii. 
Actinomycosis usually involves the cervicofacial, thoracic, abdominal, and pelvic region, dissemination is uncommon. Actinomyces viscosus are commensal organisms that make up the normal flora of the oropharynx of humans and has rarely been reported to cause disease. 
Here, we report a unique case of disseminated actinomycosis with lung and brain lesions caused by Actinomyces viscosus resembling lung cancer with metastasis in a 74-year old male. 
Cultures from skin lesions confirmed A. viscosus. 
Although the patient was immunocompromised, antibiotic treatment with a penicillin-based regimen was effective.
Lung squamous cell carcinoma (LUSC) is the most common cause of global cancer-related mortality and the major risk factors is smoking consumption. 
By analyzing ∼500 LUSC samples from The Cancer Genome Atlas, we detected a higher mutational burden as well as a higher level of methylation changes in younger patients. 
The SNPs mutational profiling showed enrichments of smoking-related signature 4 and defective DNA mismatch repair (MMR)-related signature 6 in younger patients, while the defective DNA MMR signature 26 was enriched among older patients. 
Furthermore, gene set enrichment analysis was performed in order to explore functional effect of somatic alterations in relation to patient age. 
Extracellular Matrix-Receptor Interaction, Nucleotide Excision Repair and Axon Guidance seem crucial disrupted pathways in younger patients. 
We hypothesize that a higher sensitivity to smoking-related damages and the enrichment of defective DNA MMR related mutations may contribute to the higher mutational burden of younger patients. 
The two distinct age-related defective DNA MMR signatures 6 and 26 might be crucial mutational patterns in LUSC tumorigenesis which may develop distinct phenotypes. 
Our study provides indications of age-dependent differences in mutational backgrounds (SNPs and CNVs) as well as epigenetic patterns that might be relevant for age adjusted treatment approaches.
Surgical resection has traditionally been considered the standard of care for patients with stage I non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). 
With the introduction of stereotactic radiation body therapy (SBRT), there is now a viable option for medically inoperable patients with stage I NSCLC. 
The effectiveness of SBRT in patients with stage I disease but at elevated surgical risk is unknown. 
Multiple randomized controlled trials (RCTs) have been attempted to compare surgical resection and SBRT in this population but have been aborted due to poor patient enrollment. 
Despite these failures, there still remains a push for more RCTs. 
In this commentary, we review the challenges that RCTs face in their ability to appropriately compare these two therapies.
Multidrug resistance (MDR) is a continuing clinical problem that limits the efficacy of chemotherapy in cancer. 
The over expression of the ATP-binding cassette (ABC) family G2 (ABCG2) transporter is one of the main mechanisms that mediates MDR in cancer. 
Molecular modeling data indicated that cariprazine, a dopamine D₂/D₃ receptor partial agonist, had a significant binding affinity for ABCG2 transporter with a Glide XP score of -6.515. Therefore, in this in vitro study, we determined the effect of cariprazine on MDR resulting from the overexpression of ABCG2 transporters. 
Alone, cariprazine, at concentrations up to 20 μM, did not significantly decrease cell viability. Cariprazine, at concentrations ranging from 1 to 10 μM, did not significantly alter the cytotoxicity of mitoxantrone (MX) in the parental non-small cell cancer cell line, H460 and colon cancer cell S1. 
However, cariprazine (1⁻20 μM) significantly enhanced the efficacy of ABCG2 substrate antineoplastic drug MX in the ABCG2-overexpressing MDR cell line, H460-MX20 and S1M1-80, by reducing the resistance fold from 28 to 1 and from 93 to 1.33, respectively. 
Cariprazine, in a concentration-dependent (1⁻20 μM), significantly increased the intracellular accumulation of Rhodamine 123 in S1M1-80. 
Interestingly, 10 or 20 μM of cariprazine significantly decreased the expression levels of the ABCG2 protein in the colon and lung cancer cell lines, suggesting that cariprazine inhibits both the function and expression of ABCG2 transporters at nontoxic concentrations. 
Overall, our results suggest that cariprazine, via several distinct mechanisms, can resensitize resistant cancer cells to mitoxantrone.
Mutations in the RAS/RAF/MEK/ERK pathway leading to constitutive activation and uncontrolled cellular growth have been identified in various human malignancies, making this pathway a target for potential therapeutics. 
The activating IBM Watson for Oncology (WFO), which can use natural language processing to evaluate data in structured and unstructured formats, has begun to be used in China. 
It provides physicians with evidence-based treatment options and ranks them in three categories for treatment decision support. 
This study was designed to examine the concordance between the treatment recommendation proposed by WFO and actual clinical decisions by oncologists in our cancer center, which would reflect the differences of cancer treatment between China and the U.S.
